<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:feedstersearch="http://feedster.com/feedstersearch/ext/1.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Feedster on: collective%20intelligence</title>
		<link>
			http://www.feedster.com/search/collective%20intelligence
		</link>
		<description>
			Feedster-powered RSS search result feed on:
			collective%20intelligence
		</description>
		<image>
			<link>http://feedster.com</link>
			<title>Feedster</title>
			<url>http://i.feedster.com/logo_small.png</url>
		</image>
		<managingEditor>support@feedster.com (Feedster)</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>support@feedster.com (Feedster)</webMaster>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 04:20:38 GMT</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 04:20:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<feedstersearch:totalResultCount>
			1854
		</feedstersearch:totalResultCount>
		<feedstersearch:lastArticle>
			1954526741
		</feedstersearch:lastArticle>
		<feedstersearch:pageId>
			100-FSKDCTKRTR5U-FSKDKTCZDR4F-F
		</feedstersearch:pageId>
		<textInput>
			<title>search</title>
			<description>Search on Feedster</description>
			<name>q</name>
			<link>http://feedster.com/search.php</link>
		</textInput>
		<item>
			<title>TECH TALK: The Best of 2006: 6. Mobile Web</title>
			<link>
				http://www.emergic.org/archives/2007/01/01/index.html#tech_talk_the_best_of_2006_6_mobile_web
			</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>Even as mobiles become computers, the mobile web experience leaves a lot to be desired. What will bring the breadth and depth of the web to the mobile? This is an important question, especially seen from the perspective of users in emerging markets for whom the mobile is likely to be the first and primary web access device.</p>

<p><a href=http://opengardensblog.futuretext.com/archives/2006/04/the_three_chara.html>Ajit Jaokar</a>  has been outlining what the Mobile Web 2.0 should be: <br />
<br />
I see web 2.0 as the Intelligent web or 'harnessing collective intelligence'<br />
Mobile web 2.0 extends the principle of 'harnessing collective intelligence' to restricted devices.</p>

<p>The seemingly simple idea of extending web 2.0 to mobile web 2.0 has many facets - for instance :</p>

<p>a) What is a restricted device?<br />
b) What are the implications of extending the web to restricted devices?<br />
c) As devices become creators and not mere consumers of information - what categories of intelligence can be captured/harnessed from restricted devices? <br />
d) What is the impact for services as devices start using the web as a massive information repository and the PC as a local cache where services can be configured?<br />
...<br />
Thus, the characteristics(distinguishing principles) of mobile web 2.0 are:<br />
a) Harnessing collective intelligence through restricted devices i.e. a two way flow where people carrying devices become reporters rather than mere consumers <br />b) Driven by the web backbone - but not necessarily based on the web protocols end to end<br />
c)Use of the PC as a local cache/configuration mechanism where the service will be selected and configured</p>

<p>Another way to look at this idea is to consider what is NOT mobile Web 2.0. 'Broadcast' content generated by the media industry which users are passively expected to consume: is not mobile Web 2.0. That includes most ringtones, most games, movie clips etc. <br />
<br />
More posts by Ajit can be found <a href=http://opengardensblog.futuretext.com/archives/mobile_web_20/>here</a>.</p>

<p>Tomorrow: Bottom of Pyramid Innovation</p>]]>
			</description>
			<source url="http://www.emergic.org/index.xml">
				Emergic
			</source>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 04:20:38 GMT</pubDate>
			<feedstersearch:itemWordCount>
				398
			</feedstersearch:itemWordCount>
			<feedstersearch:blogUrl>
				http://www.emergic.org/index.xml
			</feedstersearch:blogUrl>
			<feedstersearch:feedIcon></feedstersearch:feedIcon>
			<feedstersearch:guid>1954625121</feedstersearch:guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Re~Working Leadership</title>
			<link>
				http://prodigal.typepad.com/prodigal_kiwi/2007/01/reworking_leade.html
			</link>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p><strong><a onclick="window.open(this.href, '_blank', 'width=248,height=332,scrollbars=no,resizable=no,toolbar=no,directories=no,location=no,menubar=no,status=no,left=0,top=0'); return false" href="http://prodigal.typepad.com/.shared/image.html?/photos/uncategorized/an_emergent_manifesto_of_hope_cover.jpg"><img title="An_emergent_manifesto_of_hope_cover" height="133" alt="An_emergent_manifesto_of_hope_cover" src="http://prodigal.typepad.com/prodigal_kiwi/images/an_emergent_manifesto_of_hope_cover.jpg" width="100" border="0" /></a> </strong></p>

<p><strong>Paul writes </strong>" <strong>Happy New Year everyone</strong>. 9:28am on the 1st January 2007 down here at the bottom (or top, depending on your perspective) of the world. </p>

<p></p>
<p></p>

<p>Here’s an excerpt from a Dec. 2006 interview with Sally Morgenthaler…some interesting thoughts on leadership:</p>

<p><strong></strong></p>

<p></p>

<p><strong>Sally [Morgenthaler]:</strong> I've written on this subject in the soon-to-be released book, <strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Emergent-Manifesto-Hope-emersion-communities/dp/080106807X/sr=11-1/qid=1167596065/ref=sr_11_1/105-1692289-0448466">Emergent Manifesto of Hope</a></strong> (Baker, April 2007). In essence, the next form of leadership will need to break the Church's dual addictions to power and passivity. Power and passivity have taken a variety of forms since the institutionalization of Christianity about 1700 years ago. But whether in the form of priests or pastors, we still view leadership as &quot;the great man with the plan&quot; and follower-ship with paying staff to do the ministry for us. Leadership in this century will be more about convening conversation: what do the people see that needs to happen in their neighborhoods? <br /><br />What gifts do they have for meeting the needs around them? <strong>How can we gather people around a common vision and then release them to do what they're really good at doing?</strong> Business visionaries like Thomas Friedman, Max Depree, William Bergquist, Jim Collins, Marcus Buckingham, Margaret Wheatley, Stephen Covey"they've been predicting the populist, flattened world for a long time, and have been trying to orient leaders toward a radical collaboration that has conversation at its core. Even if you're not into business theory, you might be into Jesus. I know he's been labeled a CEO, but I have a hard time seeing that in light of <strong><a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Philippians%202:5-11&amp;version=65">Philippians 2: 5-11</a></strong>. Somehow, a CEO &quot;emptying himself, becoming a servant, even unto death&quot; just doesn't cut it. As we've seen with Enron, Worldcom, Adelphia, Hewlett Packard-corporate America ad nauseum"CEOs typically don't exactly move into the neighborhood and become one of us. But that's what true leadership takes…</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p>Excerpt from her chapter in <strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Emergent-Manifesto-Hope-emersion-communities/dp/080106807X/sr=11-1/qid=1167596065/ref=sr_11_1/105-1692289-0448466">An Emergent Manifesto of Hope</a></strong>:</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p>“Female Christ-followers who possess true leadership skills do not need to lead because it is politically correct. Neither do they need to lead to assuage what is most often a millimeter-thin veneer of male guilt. <strong>Women with leadership abilities need to lead because, more often than not, they get this new world and they get it really well. In a world weary of hyper individualism, top-down systems, pedestal personalities, and I-win-you-lose dichotomies, the natural feminine resonance with the flattened world"conversation, collaboration, participation, influence, presence, collective intelligence, and empowerment"has raised the cultural bar for what true leadership is and does</strong>…”</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p>Read the whole interview <strong><a href="http://www.wineskins.org/filter.asp?SID=2&amp;fi_key=149&amp;co_key=1241">here</a></strong>. Thanks to <strong><a href="http://nextreformation.com/?p=1344">Len Hjalmarson</a></strong> for the “heads up” on the issue of <strong><a href="http://www.wineskins.org/">New Wineskins</a></strong> that this interview was in.</p>

<p></p>]]>
			</description>
			<source
				url="http://prodigal.typepad.com/prodigal_kiwi/index.rdf">
				Prodigal Kiwi(s) Blog
			</source>
			<pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 20:27:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<feedstersearch:itemWordCount>
				1084
			</feedstersearch:itemWordCount>
			<feedstersearch:blogUrl>
				http://prodigal.typepad.com/prodigal_kiwi/index.rdf
			</feedstersearch:blogUrl>
			<feedstersearch:feedIcon></feedstersearch:feedIcon>
			<feedstersearch:guid>1954526741</feedstersearch:guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
